Guide to the Harry Weinberger Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Original accession, 1915-1943
  - Bales, William B.
    - Correspondence
      - Bales, James A. (6), 1918 (Box 4, Folder 1)
      - Bales, William B. (2), 1918 (Box 4, Folder 1)
      - Ballentine, Stella (5), 1918 (Box 4, Folder 1)
      - Davis, John W., 1918
        See: U.S. Department of Justice, box 4, folder 3
      - Hand, Learned (1), 1918 (Box 4, Folder 2)
      - O'Neill, Harry F. (4), 1918 (Box 4, Folder 2)
      - U.S. Department of Justice (30), 1918 (Box 4, Folder 3)
      - U.S. Supreme Court, Clerk (30), 1918 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Legal papers, 1917 (Box 4, Folder 4-5)
    - Notes (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Barnes, Djuna
    The papers consist of letters and miscellaneous papers. Weinberger was attorney for author Barnes in a dispute with the Liveright Publishing Corporation over the terms of her contract and the rights to the book Nightwood.
    - Correspondence
      - Barnes, Djuna (12), 1937-1938, 1940 (Box 4, Folder 8)
      - Harcourt, Brace, and Co. (3), 1937 (Box 4, Folder 8)
      - Liveright Publishing Corp. (5), 1937 (Box 4, Folder 9)
      - Murphy, Ray Livingstone (1), 1937 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Baron, Rose
    The papers consist of letters, legal papers, clippings, and miscellaneous papers concerning United States vs. Rose Baron, 1919-1920. Baron, an alien, was charged with being a communist and held for deportation. Weinberger secured her release because of the illegal procedure of her arrest, lack of evidence that she was a communist, and Secretary of Labor Wilson's decision that membership in the Communist Party was not grounds for deportation.
    - Correspondence
      - Baron, Rose (5), 1920 (Box 4, Folder 11)
      - New York Call (1), 1920 (Box 4, Folder 11)
      - U.S. Department of Labor, Immigration (7) (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Legal papers, 1920, undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Becker, Morris
    The papers consist of letters, legal papers, and miscellaneous papers concerning United States vs. Morris Becker, 1918-1920. While serving a term in the United States Penitentiary in Atlanta, Becker refused to register for the draft. Upon his release he was re-arrested by the Department of Justice and held for deportation by the Department of Labor as an anarchist. Weinberger got the Selective Service violation dismissed and Becker was deported to Russia with Emma Goldman and Alexander Berkman in December 1919.
    - Correspondence
      - Becker, Morris (21), 1917-1919 (Box 4, Folder 14)
      - Cohn, Michael A. (2), 1920 (Box 4, Folder 15)
      - Durkee, Harris S. (1), 1919 (Box 4, Folder 15)
      - Durkee, Warren H. (1), 1919 (Box 4, Folder 15)
      - Fitzgerald, M. Eleanor (2), 1919 (Box 4, Folder 16)
      - Jones, J. Gordon (33), 1919 (Box 4, Folder 16)
      - Merlin, M. J. (17), 1919 (Box 4, Folder 17)
      - Nathanson, Rose (2), 1918 (Box 4, Folder 17)
      - Reitman, Ben L. (3), 1919 (Box 4, Folder 17)
      - Sugar, Maurice (1), 1917 (Box 4, Folder 17)
      - U.S. Department of Justice (33), 1918-1919 (Box 4, Folder 18)
      - U.S. Department of Labor, Immigration (28), 1919 (Box 4, Folder 19)
      - U.S. District Judge, Atlanta, Georgia (1), 1919 (Box 4, Folder 19)
      - U.S. Penitentiary, Atlanta, Georgia (3), 1918 (Box 4, Folder 19)
      - U.S. Treasury Department (2), 1919 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Legal papers, 1918, undated (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Bergdoll, Grover C.
    The papers consist of letters, legal papers, notes, clippings, and miscellaneous papers. Weinberger's association with Grover Cleveland Bergdoll spans more than twenty years. Bergdoll, World War One's most infamous draft dodger, was court-martialed in 1920 and sentenced to five years confinement. Weinberger served as his attorney. In May of 1920, Bergdoll escaped and fled to Germany where he married and raised a family.
    In 1939, Bergdoll voluntarily returned to the United States. He was taken into custody by military authorities and was tried and convicted for escape and desertion. Weinberger again served as attorney. Weinberger also aided Bergdoll in other matters. He arranged the return of large amounts of Bergdoll's property that had been seized by the Alien Property Custodian. He also lobbied against a bill sponsored by Representative Forest A. Harness that would have prevented Bergdoll's return to the United States.
    Relations were not always cordial between Weinberger and his client. Conflict over Weinberger's dealings with the Alien Property Custodian prompted Bergdoll to discharge Weinberger in 1939. Weinberger brought suit against Bergdoll in 1940 to collect fees he claimed were due him.
    - Correspondence
      - A-P, R-W, Y, unidentified (355), 1920-1940 (Box 5, Folder 1-14)
      - American Civil Liberites Union (5), 1939 (Box 5, Folder 15)
      - Ansell, Samuel T. (4), 1939 (Box 5, Folder 15)
      - Baldwin, Roger N.
        See: American Civil Liberties Union, box 5, folder 15
      - Bankhead, William B. (4), 1939 (Box 5, Folder 16)
      - Barkley, Alben W. (3), 1939 (Box 5, Folder 16)
      - Barton, Bruce (3), 1939 (Box 5, Folder 16)
      - Beatty, Robert W. (9), 1940 (Box 5, Folder 17)
      - Bergdoll, Berta (35), 1938-1939, 1941-1942 (Box 5, Folder 18)
      - Bergdoll, Emma C. (85), 1920-1927, 1934, 1939 (Box 5, Folder 19-20)
      - Bergdoll, Erwin (1), 1939 (Box 5, Folder 20)
      - Bergdoll, Grover C. (135), 1920-1921, 1923-1926, 1932, 1934, 1939 (Box 5, Folder 21-23)
      - Bigelow, Arthur S. (9), 1939 (Box 5, Folder 24)
      - Borah, William E. (4), 1939 (Box 5, Folder 24)
      - Butler, Henry F. (7), 1939 (Box 5, Folder 24)
      - Callahan, James P. (3), 1939 (Box 6, Folder 1)
      - Canadian Pacific Railway Co. (2), 1939 (Box 6, Folder 2)
      - Canadian Pacific Steamship Co. (2), 1939 (Box 6, Folder 2)
      - Canadian Passport Office (4), 1939 (Box 6, Folder 2)
      - Capper, Arthur (1), 1939 (Box 6, Folder 3)
      - Celler, Emanuel (2), 1939 (Box 6, Folder 3)
      - Clark, Bennett C. (6), 1939 (Box 6, Folder 3)
      - Coffee, Harry B. (1), 1939 (Box 6, Folder 4)
      - Davis, James J. (3), 1939 (Box 6, Folder 4)
      - De Haas, George M. (4), 1939 (Box 6, Folder 4)
      - Downey, Sheridan (4), 1939 (Box 6, Folder 4)
      - Eisemann, Alex (1), 1939 (Box 6, Folder 5)
      - Faddis, Charles I. (1), 1939 (Box 6, Folder 5)
      - Farr, Chester N. (5), 1926 (Box 6, Folder 5)
      - Fish, Hamilton (4), 1939 (Box 6, Folder 5)
      - Geyer, Lee E. (1), 1939 (Box 6, Folder 6)
      - Girard, Thomas L. (9), 1920 (Box 6, Folder 6)
      - Glens Falls Indemnity Co. (11), 1941-1942 (Box 6, Folder 7)
      - Guffey, Joseph F. (3), 1939 (Box 6, Folder 7)
      - Hall, Albert (3), 1939 (Box 6, Folder 8)
      - Harness, Forest A. (3), 1939 (Box 6, Folder 8)
      - The Hecla Press (7), 1939-1940 (Box 6, Folder 8)
      - Hickok, Guy C. (1), 1939 (Box 6, Folder 8)
      - Hoover, J. Edgar (2), 1939 (Box 6, Folder 8)
      - Inglis, Agnes (3), 1939 (Box 6, Folder 9)
      - Johnson, Hiram W. (3), 1939 (Box 6, Folder 9)
      - Kiefer, Daniel (3), 1921 (Box 6, Folder 9)
      - King and King (127), 1939-1942 (Box 6, Folder 10-12)
      - LaFollette, Robert M. (6), 1939 (Box 6, Folder 13)
      - Lodge, Henry Cabot (1), 1939 (Box 6, Folder 13)
      - Marcontonio, Vito (1), 1939 (Box 6, Folder 14)
      - May, Andrew J. (3), 1939 (Box 6, Folder 14)
      - Mead, James M. (4), 1939 (Box 6, Folder 14)
      - Merritt, Matthew J. (3), 1939 (Box 6, Folder 14)
      - Murdock, William G. (31), 1939 (Box 6, Folder 15)
      - Murphy, Frank
        See: U.S. Department of Justice, box 6, folder 23
      - Norman, Dorothy (7), 1939 (Box 6, Folder 16)
      - Norris, George W. (1), 1939 (Box 6, Folder 16)
      - Nye, Gerald W. (3), 1939 (Box 6, Folder 16)
      - O'Day, Caroline (3), 1939 (Box 6, Folder 16)
      - Peters, John A. (11), 1921 (Box 6, Folder 17)
      - Robinson, D. Stuart (5), 1921 (Box 6, Folder 17)
      - Romig, James E. (12), 1920 (Box 6, Folder 17)
      - Roosevelt, Eleanor (2), 1939 (Box 6, Folder 18)
      - Roosevelt, Franklin D. (5), 1939 (Box 6, Folder 18)
      - Sabath, Adolph J. (1), 1939 (Box 6, Folder 19)
      - Sheppard, Morris (15), 1939 (Box 6, Folder 19)
      - Sherburne, John H. (2), 1921 (Box 6, Folder 19)
      - Shipstead, Henrik H. (1), 1939 (Box 6, Folder 20)
      - Sinclair, Upton (2), 1921 (Box 6, Folder 20)
      - Sirovich, William I. (4), 1939 (Box 6, Folder 20)
      - Sladovich, George (5), 1939 (Box 6, Folder 20)
      - Sommer, Frank (6), 1939 (Box 6, Folder 20)
      - Taft, Robert A. (3), 1939 (Box 6, Folder 21)
      - Tarr, Harry A. (4), 1939 (Box 6, Folder 21)
      - Thomas, Norman (3), 1920 (Box 6, Folder 21)
      - Thomson and McGinty (13), 1940 (Box 6, Folder 21)
      - Tobey, Charles W. (2), 1939 (Box 6, Folder 21)
      - U.S. Army (47), 1920-1921, 1939-1940 (Box 6, Folder 22)
      - U.S. Department of Justice (68), 1920, 1938-1940 (Box 6, Folder 23)
      - U.S. Department of Labor (13), 1939 (Box 6, Folder 24)
      - U.S. Department of State (8), 1939 (Box 6, Folder 25)
      - U.S. House of Representatives, Military Affairs Committee, Undated (Box 6, Folder 25)
      - U.S. War Department (39), 1920, 1939-1940 (Box 6, Folder 26)
      - Wadsworth, James W. (1), 1939 (Box 6, Folder 27)
      - Wagner, Robert F. (4), 1939 (Box 6, Folder 27)
      - Welsh, Bernard (7), 1941-1942 (Box 6, Folder 27)
      - Wheeler, Burton K. (2), 1939 (Box 6, Folder 28)
      - Winchell, Walter (2), 1939 (Box 6, Folder 28)
      - Winterich, John T. (3), 1939 (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - Legal papers
      Arrangement
      The legal papers, notes, clippings, and miscellaneous papers are arranged into several general sections as follows: A) Draft/ first court-martial, B) New habeas corpus, C) Second court-martial/ appeal, D) Alien property, E) Harness bill, F) Harry Weinberger vs. Bergdolls, and G) Newspaper and magazine clippings.
      These seven sections contain overlapping and related materials and are not rigid, separate files.
      A) Draft/ first court-martial: This section contains material on Bergdoll's arrest for desertion, the habeas corpus proceeding, and the 1920 court-martial.
      B) New habeas corpus: Upon his voluntary return to the United States in 1939, Bergdoll was held by military authorities. New habeas corpus proceedings were begun in 1939. These papers concern the new habeas corpus, the appeals to the Circuit Court, and, after denial there, to the Supreme Court. The petition for the writ of certiorari was prepared by Weinberger though he was no longer attorney in the case. Also filed with these papers are some documents relating to the original habeas corpus proceedings.
      C) Second court-martial/ appeal: This section contains materials used in Bergdoll's second court-martial.
      D) Alien property: This material concerns Weinberger's attempts to recover property of the Bergdoll family confiscated by the Alien Property Custodian.
      E) Harness bill: This section contains miscellaneous pamphlets, notes, and statements relating to Weinberger's activities in opposition to a bill introduced by Representative Forest A. Harness that sought to exclude from the United States persons convicted of desertion from the military while the United States is at war.
      F) Harry Weinberger vs. Bergdolls: In 1940, Weinberger brought suit against Grover Cleveland Bergdoll and his wife in an attempt to collect money due him as fees for his services as attorney. The case was settled out of court. Included in this section are early agreements and retainers.
      G) Newspaper and magazine clippings: This section contains clippings relating to Bergdoll's first arrest and court-martial, his flight to Germany, and his subsequent return to the United States and trial. Most of the clippings date from 1939.
      - A) Draft/first court-martial
        - 1918 (Box 7, Folder 1)
        - 1920-1921 (Box 7, Folder 2)
        - Undated (Box 7, Folder 3-4)
        - Testimony regarding Bergdoll (Box 7, Folder 5)
        - Notes (Box 7, Folder 6)
        - Miscellaneous (Box 7, Folder 7)
      - B) New habeas corpus
        - 1918, 1920 (Box 7, Folder 8)
        - 1939 September-December (Box 7, Folder 9-11)
        - 1940 (Box 7, Folder 12)
        - Undated (Box 7, Folder 13-14)
        - Notes (Box 8, Folder 1)
        - Miscellaneous (Box 8, Folder 2)
      - C) Second court-martial/appeal
        - 1925, 1939, 1941 (Box 8, Folder 3-4)
        - Undated (Box 8, Folder 5)
        - Exhibits (Box 8, Folder 6)
        - Notes (Box 8, Folder 7-8)
        - Miscellaneous (Box 8, Folder 9)
      - D) Alien property
        - 1938 (Box 9, Folder 1)
        - 1939, 1940-1941 (Box 9, Folder 2)
        - Undated (Box 9, Folder 3)
        - Notes (Box 9, Folder 4)
        - Miscellaneous (Box 9, Folder 4)
      - E) Harness bill
        - Miscellaneous (Box 9, Folder 5-6)
      - F) Harry Weinberger vs. Bergdolls
        - 1920-1921, 1939-1940 March (Box 9, Folder 7-9)
        - 1940 Apr, undated (Box 10, Folder 1-4)
        - Notes (Box 10, Folder 5)
        - Miscellaneous (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1918, 1920-1922, 1925-1927, 1931, 1938-1940, 1942, undated (Box 10, Folder 7-14)
  - Berkman, Alexander
    See: Goldman, Emma, box 27, folders 17-18
  - Bernstein, Ethel
    The papers consist of correspondence. Weinberger was attorney for Ethel Bernstein, Arthur Katzes, and Adolph Snoubelt, aliens held for deportation to Russia.
    - Bernstein, Ethel (2), 1919 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Shorr, Isaac (1), 1919 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - U.S. Department of Labor, Immigration (8), 1919 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Bingham, Richard E.
    The papers consist of letters, legal papers, notes, and miscellaneous papers concerning Harry E. Bingham vs. Whitmel H. Smith, 1906-1915. Weinberger represented Harry E. Bingham in a suit charging that lawyer Whitmel H. Smith had stolen funds from the estate of Richard E. Bingham.
    - Correspondence
      - Bingham, Edna (1), 1913 (Box 11, Folder 2)
      - Bingham, Mr. and Mrs. Harry E. (16), 1913-1917 (Box 11, Folder 2)
      - Bonner, A. J. (1), 1916 (Box 11, Folder 2)
      - Kempton, Edwin, Jr. (7), 1915 (Box 11, Folder 3)
      - Mackay, R. Gordon, 1913 (Box 11, Folder 3)
      - Shortt, William A. (1), 1913 (Box 11, Folder 4)
      - Smith, Whitmel H. (50), 1906, 1909, 1911-1916 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Legal papers, 1906-1915, undated (Box 11, Folder 6-8)
    - Notes (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Bobkin, Leon
    See: Derkach, Alexander, box 20, folder 12
  - Borghi, Armando
    The papers consist of letters, legal papers, and miscellaneous papers concerning United States vs. Armando Borghi, 1917-1920. Weinberger was retained by the Comitate Difesa Borghi in efforts to prevent the deportation to Italy of Armando Borghi, an antifascist.
    - Correspondence
      - American Civil Liberties Union (1), 1928 (Box 11, Folder 11)
      - Auberi, A. (1), 1928 (Box 11, Folder 11)
      - Berger, Victor L. (7), 1928 (Box 11, Folder 11)
      - Borah, William E. (4), 1938 (Box 11, Folder 11)
      - Comitato Difesa Borghi (10), 1927-1928 (Box 11, Folder 12)
      - Copelend, Royal S. (1), 1928 (Box 11, Folder 12)
      - Erwin, Charles W. (1), 1928 (Box 11, Folder 12)
      - Italian Ambassador (2), 1928 (Box 11, Folder 12)
      - LaGuardia, Fiorello H. (12), 1928 (Box 11, Folder 13)
      - Sanders, Everett (2), 1928 (Box 11, Folder 13)
      - Seldes, George S. (2), 1927 (Box 11, Folder 13)
      - U.S. Department of Labor
        See: Sanders, Everett, box 11, folder 13
    - Legal papers, 1927 (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Bosco, Paul
    The papers consist of letters, legal papers, and miscellaneous papers concerning United States vs. Paul Bosco, 1919-1921. Bosco was convicted for distributing a pamphlet entitled "The Price We Pay" and sentenced to two years in the Atlanta Penitentiary. Upon his release, Bosco was held for deportation as an anarchist. Sponsored by the Workers' Defense Union and the American Civil Liberties Union, Weinberger requested a reopening of the case on the basis of additional evidence. The arrest and deportation warrants were eventually cancelled. This case aroused widespread discussion of the rights of aliens. Included in these papers are Weinberger's replies to the attack on him by the American Legion and to Congressman Albert Johnson's speech "Alien Anarchist Set Free."
    - Correspondence
      - A, C, D, F, L, N, P-U, W (27), 1920 (Box 11, Folder 16)
      - American Civil Liberties Union (9), 1919-1920 (Box 11, Folder 17)
      - American Legion (4), 1920-1921 (Box 11, Folder 17)
      - Bosco, George (6), 1920 (Box 11, Folder 18)
      - Bosco, Paul (14), 1919-1920 (Box 11, Folder 18)
      - Castleton, Samuel M. (1), 1919 (Box 11, Folder 19)
      - De Silver, Albert, 1919
        See: American Civil Liberties Union, box 11, folder 16
      - Flynn, E.G., 1919
        See: Workers' Defense Union, box 11, folder 22
      - France, Joseph I. (3), 1920 (Box 11, Folder 19)
      - Gneiser, G. A. (10), 1919-1920 (Box 11, Folder 19)
      - Johnson, Albert (17), 1920 (Box 11, Folder 20)
      - Johnson, Royal C. (2), 1920 (Box 11, Folder 20)
      - LaFollette, Robert M. (2), 1920 (Box 11, Folder 21)
      - Mason, William E. (4), 1920 (Box 11, Folder 21)
      - Ralston, Jackson H. (4), 1920 (Box 11, Folder 21)
      - Sinclair, Upton (1), 1920 (Box 11, Folder 22)
      - U.S. Department of Labor, Immigration (34), 1920 (Box 11, Folder 22)
      - Watson, Thomas E. (2), 1920 (Box 11, Folder 22)
      - Workers' Defense Union (7), 1920 (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - Legal papers, 1920, undated (Box 11, Folder 23)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - Bottvinick, Edka
    The papers consist of letters, legal papers, and miscellaneous papers concerning United States vs. Edka Bottvinick, 1920. Bottvinick was charged with being an anarchist and a member of the Communist Party, and held for deportation. Weinberger had the warrant of deportation cancelled because of lack of evidence.
    - Correspondence
      - Bottvinick, Edka (Itka) (7), 1920 (Box 12, Folder 1)
      - Bottvinick, Elias (3), 1920 (Box 12, Folder 1)
      - Dorf, Max (2), 1920 (Box 12, Folder 1)
      - U.S. Department of Labor, Immigration (8), 1920 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Legal papers, 1920, undated (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Bureau of Legal First Aid (3), 1917 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    The papers consist of correspondence between Weinberger and the Bureau of Legal First Aid.
  - Buzzi, Alfredo
    The papers consist of letters and miscellaneous papers. Weinberger was retained by the Italian Workers' Defense League to represent Buzzi, a conscientious objector sentenced to fifteen years of hard labor (later commuted to four) for disobeying an order. Weinberger obtained amnesty for Buzzi, after he had served two years three months of his sentence.
    - Correspondence
      - Buzzi, Alfredo (4), 1920 (Box 12, Folder 5)
      - Italian Defense League (11), 1920 (Box 12, Folder 5)
      - U.S. War Department (17), 1920 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Campeo, Tomaso
    The papers consist of letters and miscellaneous papers concerning New York vs. Tomaso Campeo, 1919. Weinberger acted as attorney for Tomaso Campeo, charged with carrying a revolver.
    - Correspondence
      - Campeo, Tomaso (Thomas) (2), 1919 (Box 12, Folder 7)
      - Ciafolo, Andrea (1), 1919 (Box 12, Folder 7)
      - U.S. Department of Justice (2), 1919 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Cape Playhouse, Inc.
    The papers consist of letters, legal papers, notes, and miscellaneous papers. Weinberger served as the legal advisor and attorney for the Cape Playhouse and the Cape Playhouse Cinema, Dennis, Cape Cod, Massachusetts. Weinberger also served as personal attorney for owner Raymond Moore.
    - Correspondence
      - A-C, E-H, K, N, P, T, W (40), 1928-1931, 1940 (Box 12, Folder 9)
      - Actor's Equity Association (11), 1929 (Box 12, Folder 10)
      - First National Bank of Yarmouth (7), 1928-1929 (Box 12, Folder 10)
      - Fitzgerald, Cora E. (20), 1930-1931 (Box 12, Folder 11)
      - Fogarty, Alexander (4), 1929-1930 (Box 12, Folder 11)
      - Godall Electric Co. (4), 1931 (Box 12, Folder 12)
      - Horn Folding Partition Co. (35), 1930-1931 (Box 12, Folder 12)
      - Martin, George W. (10), 1930-1931 (Box 12, Folder 13)
      - Massachusetts, Commonwealth of (42), 1928-1930 (Box 12, Folder 13)
      - Mielziner, Jo (5), 1930-1931 (Box 12, Folder 14)
      - Moore, Edgar W. (9), 1928-1929 (Box 12, Folder 14)
      - Moore, Raymond (120), 1928-1934, 1940 (Box 12, Folder 15-16)
      - Murphy, Walter P. (4), 1931 (Box 12, Folder 16)
      - New England Telephone Co. and Telegraph Co. (11), 1931 (Box 12, Folder 17)
      - New York Title and Mortgage Co. (8), 1930 (Box 12, Folder 17)
      - Nickerson Lumber Co. (13), 1928, 1940 (Box 12, Folder 17)
      - Paxton, Sidney (7), 1929 (Box 12, Folder 18)
      - Sabbotovsky, Boris (4), 1930 (Box 12, Folder 18)
      - Schubert Theatre Corp. (4), 1928 (Box 12, Folder 18)
      - Tweedy, Edna B. (8), 1931 (Box 12, Folder 19)
      - U.S. Department of Justice (4), 1929-1930 (Box 12, Folder 19)
      - U.S. Treasury Department (3), 1929 (Box 12, Folder 19)
      - Wharton, John F. (5), 1932-1933 (Box 12, Folder 20)
      - Wilson, Kenneth E. (9), 1939-1940 (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - Legal Papers, 1928-1931 (Box 13, Folder 1-4)
    - Notes (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Carruthers, Gloria
    The papers consist of letters, legal papers, notes, and miscellaneous papers concerning Gloria Carruthers vs. Loew's Inc., 1938-1940. Weinberger served as attorney for Gloria Carruthers, an entertainer and mentalist known professionally as Zuleika. Carruthers brought charges against Loew's Inc. for defamation of character and loss of income caused by the presentation of a character, Zuleika, as a phony and drunk seeress in the MGM motion picture Idiot's Delight. She was awarded $1000 damages.
    - Correspondence
      - Carruthers, Gloria (Zuleika) (9), 1939-1940 (Box 13, Folder 7)
      - Cherio (4), 1940 (Box 13, Folder 8)
      - Dr. Fredericks (1), 1940 (Box 13, Folder 8)
      - Jones, William F. (9), 1939-1940 (Box 13, Folder 8)
      - Metro Goldwyn Mayer Pictures, Legal department (9), 1940 (Box 13, Folder 9)
      - Munsell, Warren P. (2), 1940 (Box 13, Folder 9)
      - Ramey, Deane (3), 1940 (Box 13, Folder 10)
      - Schwartz, George M. (3), 1940 (Box 13, Folder 10)
      - Sherwood, Robert (2), 1940 (Box 13, Folder 10)
      - Shorell, Herbert L. (3), 1939-1940 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Legal papers, 1938-1940, undated (Box 13, Folder 11-14)
    - Notes (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Chenenky, Lena
    The papers consist of letters and legal papers concerning United States vs. Lena Chenenky, 1920-1922. Lena Chenenky was charged with being an anarchist and a member of the Communist Party and held for deportation. Weinberger succeeded in having the warrant for deportation cancelled due to a lack of evidence.
    - Correspondence
      - Chenenky, Lena (12), 1920, 1922 (Box 14, Folder 1)
      - Cohen, Herbert (1), 1920 (Box 14, Folder 1)
      - U.S. Department of Labor, Immigration (4), 1920 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Legal papers, 1920, undated (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Cheney, Sheldon